soundradix.com 2019-05-20

# Privacy Policy | Sound Radix

#### Introduction

Last Updated: November 19, 2018

This privacy policy (“Policy”) describes how Sound Radix, Ltd. (“Sound Radix”, “We”, “Us”, “Our”) collects, uses, protects and shares information in the Sound Radix website (the “Site”) and in Sound Radix products and services. It also tells you about your rights regarding your Personal Data. We are the sole owner of the information collected on your use of the Site, products or services. We will not sell or rent this information to others. We may only share this information in ways specified in this Policy.

Sound Radix is committed to protecting your Personal Data in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation - (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR).

By using the Site, you consent to the terms of this Policy. We reserve the right to make changes to this Policy at any time. If we make changes to our Policy, we will notify our users. If at any time you do not accept the Policy, please do not use our Site; we would appreciate it if you contact us at our support to share your stance and hopefully we could improve our policy to accommodate your needs. In case we make changes to the Policy, your continued use of our Site following our notification about the changes will mean you accept those changes.

#### What Is Personal Data and Who Is Responsible for It?

Personal Data is information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual. Sound Radix is responsible for the handling of any Personal Data which we collect from you. Along with our distributors, dealers and service providers, we are also responsible for how we handle Personal Data which we collect from them. We encourage you to read our service providers’ privacy policies to learn more about how they handle your Personal Data.

#### Personal Data Collected and Its Use

Sound Radix stores your name, email address and salted hash of the password which you enter at account creation time. We use your email address and password salted hash to enable authentication to the Site. We also use your email address to send you emails essential to using the Site and our products, e.g., post-purchase instructions and license redeem codes. We use your name for personalization of your experience on the Site, e.g., displaying your name in the top bar on the Site.

We may send you updates on Sound Radix special offers, products and events by email if you have subscribed to receive such emails by checking the newsletter subscription checkbox at account creation time, subscribing from the SUBSCRIBE section in the Site footer, or directly contacting Sound Radix staff. (Note: The checkbox on account creation is now unchecked by default, so checking it means explicit consent; prior to May 21st, 2018 it was checked by default, so consent granted by it was implicit. Since GDPR requires consent for sending non-essential emails to be explicit, we have not taken into account implicit consent granted by the checkbox prior to May 21st, 2018 for sending emails to individuals in the EU and EEA). We may also send you updates on Sound Radix special offers, products and events by email if you have implictly consented to receive such emails prior to May 21st, 2018 and have purchased at least one Sound Radix product. You may unusbscribe from the email updates at any time from your Account Settings, by clicking the unsubscribe link in one the emails, or by directly contacting us at Sound Radix support.

[SendInBlue](https://www.sendinblue.com/) is our service provider for sending all emails essential to using our Site and our products, e.g., post-purchase instructions and license redeem codes. For that purpose, we will share your email address with SendInBlue. We also use SendInBlue’s service to send our email updates on Sound Radix special offers, products and events. If you subscribe to receive such updates, we will also share your name with SendInBlue in order to provide that service.

[Freshworks, Inc.](https://www.freshworks.com/) (“Freshworks”) is our service provider for serving our support site. We use Freshworks’s [Freshdesk](https://freshdesk.com/) service to serve our support site. For that purpose, we will share your name and email address with Freshworks if you login to the support site. Since our support site is hosted by Freshworks, when you access our support site your IP address, operating system and platform and browser will be shared with Freshworks (that information is visible to any site you visit on the internet). If you open a support ticket, you or we may share additional Personal Data on the support site to enable providing you with good customer support. Please note any such additional Personal Data will also be accessible by Freshworks and subject to [Freshworks’s privacy policy](https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/). 

[Paypal Holdings, Inc.](https://www.paypal.com/us/home) (“PayPal”) is our service provider to facilitate purchases from the site. Sound Radix stores a record of purchases you make from the site and stores in its purchase record contact information received from PayPal. Information we store may include your name, business name, email address, address and phone number. This information is only used for accounting and compliance purposes.

[PACE Anti-Piracy Inc.](https://www.paceap.com/) (“PACE”) is our service provider for authorization and copy protection of our products. Sound Radix stores your PACE User ID and PACE email address when you redeem a license code for a PACE-protected product. It also sends these credentials to the PACE authentication server in order to deposit a license in your PACE account. Your PACE User ID and PACE email address, as well as the response from the the PACE authentication server, are stored by Sound Radix to enable troubleshooting in case of failed activations.

We may collect your Personal Data from a third-party when you enter a competition or promotion run by the third-party, in case you have permitted the third-party to share your Personal Data. We will only use this information for contact details for delivering prizes or providing related services and/or products.

If you purchase a Sound Radix product from a distributor, you will receive a license redeem code for activating the product in your account. Once you redeem your license code, the distributor will be able to view your name, email address, the redeemed license code and its redeem date on the Site to help Sound Radix and the distributor to provide better customer support.

The third-party vendors [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/) and [Google LLC](https://www.google.com/) (“Google”) are our service providers for analyzing activity on our Site and for serving and optimizing the placement and content of Sound Radix advertisements. If you explicitly enable third-party cookies, Sound Radix allows tools from these vendors to store cookies and run cookie-related scripts in your browser when visiting our Site. You can enable third-party cookies either on the pop-up asking to enable them (presented on every page in the Site until you either explicitly enable them or opt-out) or in your Account Settings. These cookies may be sent to their matching third-party vendors whenever you visit the Site. The information third-party vendors may derive when you enable third-party cookies may include, but is not limited to, your:

  1. \- IP address 
  2. \- Operating system and platform 
  3. \- Browser 
  4. \- Times of visits to our Site 
  5. \- Pages viewed and time spent on each page 
  6. \- Information about your actions in our Site 

Such cookies are considered Personal Data because they may be used by the third-party vendors to create a user profile. Enabling third-party cookies allows us to gain a better understanding of how our users use our Site and make improvements to the Site accordingly. The third-party vendors may use the information about your visits to the Sound Radix Site to place targeted Sound Radix advertisements on other sites you visit, as well as provide Sound Radix with data about the effectiveness of such advertisements. You can opt-out of third-party cookies at any time from your Account Settings. Please note that opting-out of third-party cookies will immediately stop sending them to the third-party vendors and stop running the third-party cookie-related scripts, but will not clear previously existing cookies in the browser since Sound Radix cannot do that technically: we have no permission or control to clear cookies on the third-party domains. You can, however, clear previously existing third-party cookies by performing a “Clear Cookies” operation in your browser.

Some pages on the Sound Radix Site include embedded content from Google’s [YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/) service and from SoundCloud Limited’s [SoundCloud](https://soundcloud.com/) service. When you visit pages which include such embedded content, your IP address, operating system and platform and browser will be shared with these third-party vendors (that information is visible to any site you visit on the internet, including those served as embedded content). These third-party vendors may also set their own cookies in your browser if you visit their sites or otherwise. If you have a third-party vendor’s cookies already stored in your browser, and you then visit a page on the Sound Radix Site which includes that vendor’s embedded content, the third-party vendor may use its cookies to track your visit to the page. According to tests we performed on June 25, 2018, interaction with YouTube and SoundCloud embedded content on our Site which does not make another request to the third-party vendor (such as viewing the third-party vendor’s service’s own site in a new browser window) will not create and store new third-party cookies in your browser if you did not already have such cookies stored beforehand. For example, simply playing an embedded YouTube video or SoundCloud track will not create and store new cookies in your browser.

Sound Radix stores its own essential cookies in your browser. There is no way to opt-out of these cookies, because they are essential to the Site’s operation. For example, a cookie is stored to maintain your authentication. Another cookie stores your choice to enable/opt-out of third-party cookies in case you have not yet authenticated, so that once you authenticate your choice can be read from the cookie and stored in your Account Settings. The essential cookies are never shared with anyone outside of Sound Radix.

#### Non-Personal Data Collected and Its Use

Some of our legacy products generate a license ID value during installation. The license ID is sent to and stored by Sound Radix, as well as stored locally on the installing machine. The license ID does not contain any specific information about you or the data on your computer.

Sound Radix products, when launched, may make an update check API call to the Sound Radix Site to notify you of an update to your product if one is available. The update check payload contains a hash of the executable, needed to determine whether an update is available. For some legacy products, the update check payload also contains the aforementioned license ID. Sound Radix stores the update checks and their payloads. Storing the executable hashes allows us to troubleshoot issues with either updates or the product in general, as well as perform usage statistics of the different products versions. Storing the license ID helps us with customer support, allowing us to clear an authorization of an old (possibly no-longer-available) machine in case your license allowance is exhausted and you wish to authorize your product on a new machine instead of the old one.

#### Data Integrity and Security

Sound Radix protects against the loss, misuse and/or alteration of data located on our systems by using several industry standard security measures:

  1. \- Only using encrypted connections from and to our Site
  2. \- Updating our server backend to take advantage of up-to-date protections against new threats
  3. \- Taking advantage of security measures offered by Heroku and Cloudflare
  4. \- Regularly reviewing our security model and configuration
  5. \- Avoiding storing data we don't need

Please note it is impossible to completely guarantee the security of data transmissions over the Internet in general. Therefore, while we will always do our best to protect your Personal Data, any submission of data is at your own risk.

#### Personal Data Disclosure

Sound Radix may share your Personal Data if it must do so in the context of fraud investigations, or in order to respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process.

We may also share pertinent Personal Data in case of an emergency, to protect our employees and agents, our customers, or any other person.

If we are involved in an acquisition, a merger or an asset sale, Personal Data may be shared with the acquiring entity or successor-in-interest.

#### Lawful Grounds

Sound Radix’s lawful grounds for using your Personal Data include explicit consent and the following legitimate interests (in some cases coupled with implicit consent):

  1. \- Understanding how our customers use our products and services
  2. \- Developing and improving our products and services 
  3. \- Growing our business
  4. \- Providing customer support
  5. \- Reducing our marketing costs

An additional lawful ground for processing is legal obligations.

#### Your Rights

Under certain conditions, you may have rights in relation to your Personal Data, detailed below. If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please contact us at Sound Radix support.

You have the right to:

  1. \- **Request access**  to your Personal Data. We will send you a copy of all of your Personal Data which we have stored.
  2. \- **Request correction**  of any inaccuracies in the Personal Data we have stored about you.
  3. \- **Request erasure**  of your Personal Data. We will erase your account and remove all of your Personal Data which we have stored. (Note: If you ask to completely remove your account, we may no longer be able to provide you with service and support for any previously purchased products.)
  4. \- **Request restriction of processing**  of your Personal Data while we consider an inquiry you have made.
  5. \- **Object to processing** of your Personal Data which is based on legitimate interest, unless our legitimate interest outweights your interests, rights and freedoms. Note that with regards to email updates, you may unusbscribe from email updates at any time by unsubscribing from your Account Settings, by clicking the unsubscribe link in one the emails, or by directly contacting us at Sound Radix support.
  6. \- **Withdraw consent** at any time where we are relying on consent to process your Personal Data. We will stop any processing of data which was previously based on your consent. Note this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing done before you withdraw your consent.
  7. \- **Make a complaint** to the supervisory authority for data protection issues in your country. Before filing such a complaint you are always welcome to first contact us at Sound Radix support, where we will do our best to address any issue.

#### Identity Confirmation

To exercise any of your rights we may need to request information from you to let us confirm your identity. This is a security measure to ensure that your Personal Data would only be disclosed to you.

#### Sound Radix Public Forum

This Policy does not protect information you post to the public Sound Radix forum. Logging in to the forum uses Single-Sign-On with the Sound Radix Site authentication, so if you login to the forum your name on the Sound Radix Site will be shared publicly on the forum.

#### Other Sites

Sound Radix contains links to other, external websites. Sound Radix has no control over these external websites and is not responsible for any content or privacy issues in these sites, nor for any interaction you make with these sites.

#### Children’s Privacy

We do not allow children younger than 13 to register as users and we will not knowingly collect Personal Data from children younger than 13. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that Personal Data and their account. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at Sound Radix support. 

#### Contact Information

For any questions or comments about this Policy, please contact us at Sound Radix support.
